[music]
Uh, thank you everyone for coming out.
Uh, my name is Aiden Knife. I live here
in Brooklyn. Uh, so not too far. Um, and
for everyone who travel in, thank you
for coming to our lovely city for this.
It's been a great event so far. Um, so
I'm going to talk a little bit about how
to track the AI generated code uh that
is in everyone's repos being written all
day by these coding agents. Um, so
anyone figure out this code stuff?
Everyone using it, I assume if you're
here. Okay, cool. Um, so I uh always
every conference talk I do, I always
come up with an alternative title that's
more fun. Um, this is one of my favorite
Steve Jobs quotes. Um, he said that a
computer is like the bicycle for our
minds. Um and uh what he meant by that
was basically that a bicycle is just
hung of metal. It doesn't go very fast.
Humans don't go very fast, but together
um they go faster than any animal in the
animal kingdom. And that was his
metaphor for how technology can make us
better. So when all this coding agent
stuff hit in the beginning of the year
um and people started using it, um I
felt like there was this like massive
opportunity, but I had no idea how to
bike and juggle these three things and
get the most out of it. I felt like
sometimes I'd hit enter and two hours
later I had made no progress and then
other times I'd hit enter and things
worked really great and I was like, "Oh,
this is amazing." Like the whole world's
changed now. Um, so I wanted to get a
little more scientific about this. And
over the 4th of July when fireworks were
going on, I was writing uh all kinds of
silly code trying to figure out um how
to get better and use data from my
agents to become a better programmer.
Um, so I wanted to know basically like
what percent of my code was actually
written by AI. Were the bugs that I was
finding caused by AI code that I just
sort of approved without looking at it?
Um, how much my code did I end up
rewriting? And then what magical
prompting techniques that I was copying
off Twitter actually worked? Can I prove
this with data? Um, so I'm like a very
sciency numbers guy. I was like, I need
real data to figure this out. Uh, so I
log in to the dashboards for all the
agents and I find stuff like this. Um,
it says, you know, you generated 45,000
lines of code this week, but then I look
at GitHub and it's like, well, only
6,000 made it in. Um, so the data was
just really, really bad. I don't know if
they're overounting it for business
reasons or it's just a really hard
technical problem. Um, but I didn't find
this to be very useful. And then all the
tools I tried to use to detect AI code
using AI that all felt like fighting
fire with fire and it just was very
expensive as well. So um it felt like
there were no good approaches for doing
this. So I had the thought that I think
every developer has late at night which
is it's time to rewrite git. Um [snorts]
luckily I amended uh that line a little
bit and I wrote a git extension instead.
Um so that git extension is called git
AI. You install it um on your computer
and then whenever one of these agents
writes code it will um basically mark
the AI generated lines um as sort of
generated by AI and then get AI the
extension will track that. So it'll go
through merges rebases cherrypicks all
the nasty evil stuff that you can do to
commits and diffs. Um, Git AI will
preserve the authorship through all
those real world workflows. So, let me
show you real quick how this works. Um,
I'm going to bop over to cursor. This is
our actual project. Um, so the Git AI
project is actually using Git AI. So,
you can see like what AI code in the
project um was generated, what stuff we
wrote by hand, what stuff was written by
AI, and then we had to like overwrite.
We've learned a lot looking at all of
this. Um, so I'll just run this real
quick prompt. Um, we work crossplatform,
so we have a lot of like Windows
compatibility stuff we have to do. Um,
and we're starting to look at WSL and
making that support better. So, I'm
going to have it generate a quick helper
for me to detect uh WSL. So, there we
go. Magic cursor did it for me with
composer. Um, and I'll just commit this
normally.
Wrote a couple lines there. Um, and I'll
just call it WSL. Um, check
Great. And it told me that a 100% of
that code was written by AI. Um there's
this little bar graph that is uh filled
in based on how much I write versus how
much the AI writes. And then when I do
get AI blame and I open uh this file,
you'll see all of these Aenk Kniff and
Sasha lines. And then at the bottom,
these are all from cursor. Um so it's
tracking that AI code really accurately.
Um, and it's doing this by attaching git
notes um to every single commit. And
those git notes look like this.
Um, let's grab this commit jaw.
Cool. So, it basically will find all of
the lines that each prompt generated.
So, we're not just tracking the lines
that were written by AI. We're actually
tracking uh the lines um and associating
them with the prompt that generated
them. And this is basically saying, hey,
in this commit at this point in time,
2FC, uh, lines 52 through 91
were generated by this prompt right
here. Um, and because it's in Git notes,
it's going to be shared with all of my
collaborators, so they can see um,
basically the AI code I generated, too.
Cool. All right, so back to the slides.
Um
that was my backup because the demo gods
aren't always nice to people. Um I'm
going to talk a little bit about how
this works. So um we've actually been
working with cursor and teams at some of
the other agents uh cloud code copilot
uh some of the smaller ones and
basically directly um integrating so
that when these tools generate um AI
code it calls get AAI and will basically
mark their code as AI generated. Um it
does this basically by using hooks in a
lot of them and then some of the agents
have a direct integration where they
basically call us and say these lines
were written by AI and then the
responsibility of the Git AI project is
to store these in the notes make sure
they get synced back and forth properly
with the upstreams um and then make sure
that um when you do all of these gnarly
things like reset and rebase and merge
and cherrypick the notes are synced um
and sort of merge rewritten accurately.
So when you're using these real world
git workflows, Gitai is able to track
that code going forward.
Cool. Sweet. Um so the goal here uh is
to build this so it's open source and
multi- aent. Um most of the companies
that have started to adopt this use two,
three, four, five, sometimes all you can
eat or built their own agents. So it's
really important if we're going to be
measuring AI code to be able to look at
all these agents and sort of the same
views with the same kind of data. So
that's been a really big sort of um
important piece of the project. We also
really believe in being explicit. Um
there are a lot of people building tools
like this that are heruristic driven and
try to guess what AI code is. um we've
just been knocking on doors, reaching
out to the people building the agents
and getting them to support it. And
they've all been very happy to work with
us um and support like a community
standard around this. So we're hoping to
build like the community standard here
for um tracking AI code. We've also made
it git native uh for all the reasons I
talked about. There are a lot of real
world workflows. uh we all use git every
day and we shouldn't go around and um
have to change that core part of the
SDLC just because we want to start
tracking AI code and saving our prompts.
So what's been the value for me? Like
have I learned to ride my bike? Um I
think for uh the teams I'm working on
and some of the early users, everyone's
gotten a lot of value out of
understanding um how much of this ROI
that they're sort of seeking um is
coming from different agents. they can
see, oh, this one's working better for
this team or this kind of code or this
language. Um, people can start to
understand a lot more um about which
teams are using AI the best and who's
getting better, all this stuff. Uh,
that's really important, especially with
how much all of these tools cost. Um,
I've also found it really useful during
code review. Um, everyone I've talked to
who uses it has told me that they review
code differently based on whether an AI
wrote it or whether a human wrote it.
And more than once I've gone and run
that blame command and found out, oh,
like that's why that code is the way it
is. Like now I understand it. I can see
like what the prompt was and what the
intent was behind this block of code.
Um, and then I'm starting to to get
here. I definitely have learned a lot,
but um, understanding like what kind of
prompting actually works. Um, it was a
lot of guessing before. It was a lot of
vibes like, oh, let's do it this way
because this was the latest tweet I saw.
Um, but now I feel like I'm starting to
build better instincts about how to work
with these tools. And I've gone from um
the old style which was just like type
10 pages and hit enter to this like kind
of new iterative style where I kind of
work with it like a companion. Um, and
it's definitely taught me sort of how to
how to focus on the right approach for
different kinds of tasks as well.
So looking ahead, um, I guess what we're
hoping to do with this project is two
things. Um, one is making the agent
smarter and one is making the human
smarter. Uh, this is back to the
bicycle. Um, but we really believe that
like an average model with better
context is going to beat an awesome
model with poor context. And there's a
lot of really really valuable context in
these prompts. Like developers are
literally spending all day writing them
now. Um, being able to work uh with
those prompts later, it's kind of silly
like that we just throw them away. there
must be valuable context there. Um, so I
think we can make the agents 10, 20, 30
IQ points smarter just by storing that
information in a useful way and making
it available for future prompts. So
that's still very experimental. Don't
have a good answer there yet, but we see
it as like a really cool thing to build
the project towards. Another thing is
this prompting. Uh, like I said before,
like I've already learned a lot about
prompting and I want to make more of
those insights available to other
engineers who are using these tools
every day. Um, and same thing I was
saying before, I think an engineer who
knows how to work with coding agents
armed with an average model is going to
beat an engineer who doesn't really know
the best way to work with the agents who
has an awesome model. So I think this is
a interesting fun primitive that will
help us uh both get smarter and help um
the agents get a lot smarter too. So
that's Git AI. Um you can start using it
today. It's open source. there's a
download in blue and if you want to talk
to me about this or anything else
there's talk to me in red. So thank you
guys so much. Um have a few minutes for
questions and appreciate you all coming
to the talk.
[applause]
Uh you are first and then we'll come
over here.
>> So you mentioned that you're you're
capturing the prompt as well in the in
the git notes. Did I hear that correct?
Yes, we do.
>> Okay. Is there like any limit? Like what
if that prompt happens to be some kind
of massive
uh context dump workflow set of
instructions? You're still capturing all
of that.
>> Yeah. So, we capture like all of the
messages and all the tool calls, but
we're not capturing um the rights since
it's all ending up in git anyway. And um
we're not doing tool results either cuz
that probably doesn't uh do much anymore
and there could be like information in
there that you don't want to share. So
we found that when you take that stuff
out like they end up being pretty small.
Um but right now yeah there's not like a
hard limit on that. You could have a
conversation or get pretty long.
>> Okay. And then one other question around
like you showed the um get AI blame
command.
>> Is that available like in GitHub? Is
there any kind of like web based
extension or like if I'm looking at a
repo am I seeing that context like at
that level or just locally?
>> So right now it's local. Um I have been
talking to some of the SEM tools about
this. Um since the data is in the notes
they could use it too. Um obviously that
like doesn't happen overnight. Um but if
people open issues and talk to them as
well and create momentum uh I could see
people adopting it. It's been really
useful for me to like pull it down and
look at it myself.
>> Okay, thank you.
>> Of course. Um, there you go.
>> Any more questions?
>> Yeah.
>> Um, how do you think about some of the
like growing cloud AI agents working
with these kind of workflows? Because
like right now it's like you install it
on your machine, it integrates with the
git CLI or whatever. Let's say I'm using
cloud code in the web or AI studio from
Gemini. Like obviously all that code's
AI generated, some of it might end up in
Git. Do you have any thoughts about how
you might integrate with that kind of
thing?
>> Yeah, I think it's going to look very
similar. Um you like those have authors
so they um usually they'll commit if it
is in a repo and they'll like put like a
something atgoogle.com email. Um, so we
could probably have like a heruristic
where we look for those specific emails
like codeex at OpenAI Gemini at Google
and then just sort of add our own like
little annotation to map that back to
get good AI. I still think a lot of that
code you end up fetching locally doing
stuff on top of and then we have this
concept of mixed authorship which is
when an AI writes something and a human
changes it. Um, so hopefully we can get
all that information to play nicely
together.
>> Great question. Um, and you're in the
back afterward. Uh yeah, I was just
curious on one of your first slides, you
talked about the question of, you know,
how often is my AI code getting
rewritten by a human, let's say, like
have you collected any data on that and
what are your findings and in starting
to look into this type of thing?
>> Yeah, so a blog post coming soon. Um I I
the the rough anecdotal data I have is
that it was a lot worse. So when I was
prompting um like bigger oneshot
prompts, uh I was going back and
rewriting a lot of that code later. And
then as I got more specific and was
doing things more like function or one
test at a time, um it was it was going
down. So it was something like 60%, it's
probably closer now to around 20% over
the course of like a week or two. Um
we're going to start publishing a lot
more of this kind of stuff on our blog
um as more of the big companies who use
it uh share that data with us.
>> Cool. Um this is a pretty amazing tool.
As soon as I read about that and
realized this assist yesterday, I went
straight I had to install that and tell
my boss as well. And then after I
installed everything, I realized that it
doesn't work with codeex yet. Um because
it seems that we are waiting for hooks
for implementation for that. But also
put me into thinking, have you thought
of approaches that can work regardless
of the um agent that someone might be
using or how they configure the tools or
are you essentially like blog to be like
in a partnership with them so that they
add logic in order to allow you to sort
of like hook in get the AI code.
>> Yeah. So, I think the the goal right now
with the project like we have to prick
pick some principles and one of the ones
that we're really trying to get behind
is to be super explicit and not try to
guess which code comes from AI. Um, so
that's like a I think that that's one of
those things where it's going to have a
slower ramp like we have to go talk to
all these agents and get them on board.
A month ago we had no no support
basically. Now we have a lot more. I
think in a month or two we'll have, you
know, much better coverage than we do
today. Um, but I think it's a good
long-term bet because ultimately I don't
want like um fuzzy data about what come
from the AI. I want very explicit data
and I want to know exactly which prompt
led to which lines of code. Great
question.
>> All right, another question. Yes,
>> just a following
code.
Um can you sorry can you ask it again?
>> Um yes I was wondering if you had
thought about what would happen if the
um agent of like start implementing
their own solution for tracking their
own code as opposed to like just um
getting support for this implemented.
>> Yeah. So we've talked to a few companies
uh like the question was have you
thought about what happens agents start
to implement their own standard for for
tracking code. Um we've talked to a few
companies that are adopting this like
big 10,000 person plus companies um that
have been rolling this out over the last
couple weeks. Um and also a lot of these
agent companies and I think right now
like um everyone's very multi- aent and
nobody wants just the data from one and
then the data from the other. They want
to compare the agents to each other.
They want to see [snorts] how each is
performing and they want to have one
like cohesive place where all this data
is stored. So I think the bet is that
this stuff is going to remain kind of
outside of any one agent. Um it might be
wrong but that's kind of the game we're
playing and we're trying to work really
well with the rest of the ecosystem.
>> Awesome. Thank you.
>> I would actually say we need like a
standard way of telemetry like we have
on machines hotel but for coding agents
and you know they will align on
something I would say. Um there was a
story once from the the folks I think it
was all hands who presented somewhere
that said um we refrained from
committing code as the agent.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh because that actually um got like
worse at people not looking at the PRs.
>> Uh so it's an interesting observation
kind of like you know that like you can
store it in a node but the committer can
still be the human.
>> That that's kind of a you know a side
note to that. Yeah. Yeah, it definitely
works. You see both. You can see like
the responsible human who like merged it
and generated it and then the agent who
helped them do the work.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think another extension would be
cool for you is um so people have been
checking whether one LLM is better than
the code than the other. And so they
typically change the whole workflow and
they do it. Well, I I know of one
extension, a VS Code extension that
measures it by saying they present
actually the two solutions from this LLM
and the other LLM and then they say this
one was better. So, if there would be a
way to capture this, then you actually
also kind of anecdental telemetry of
what is actually the best coding agent
in there. So,
>> yeah. Yeah, definitely. I think helping
people pick the right agent for the job
is part of making people smarter. And I
think uh there's a lot of great data we
can use to make the agents smarter, too.
So, it's been super fun and uh yeah,
hopefully this is useful for everyone
and their teams.
>> Yeah, thanks for sharing. Good talk.
Yeah,
>> awesome. Thank you.
[applause]
[music]